Guide to the Charles Solomon Papers TAM.041
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Charles Solomon Papers
1916-1965
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Solomon, Charles
TAM.041
2.25 Linear Feet (5 boxes)
Charles Solomon was a socialist, a New York State Assemblyman, and a New York City magistrate. Contains correspondence, legal papers relating to matters brought before Solomon as magistrate, manuscripts, clippings and scrapbooks.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
Charles Solomon was a socialist, a New York State Assemblyman (1919-1921) and a New York City magistrate (1936-1945, 1950-1959). He was one of five assemblymen expelled by the New York State Legislature in 1920 for being a Socialist. He was re-elected that same year. He later ran unsuccessfully as a Socialist candidate for governor, senator, and New York City mayor before joining the Liberal Party.
Scope and Content Note
The papers include correspondence (including individual letters from Morris Hillquit and Harry Laidler), legal papers relating to matters brought before Solomon as magistrate, manuscripts of writings, radio scripts, addresses, published articles, printed debates including one with Scott Nearing, clippings (including some in Yiddish), and scrapbooks.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I, Papers (arranged alphabetically: II, Scrapbooks (arranged alpabetically, then chronologically); Series III, Fragile Originals (arranged by box number).
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated (probably by Charles Solomon's daughters Mildred Clinton and Isabel Moros) in 1965. The accession number associated with this gift is 1965.004. Additional materials related to Solomon were found in Tamiment's collections in 2014. The accession number associated with these materials is 2014.048.
Separated Material
Photographs were separated to the Charles Solomon Photographs (PHOTOS 008)
Obituaries.; Socialism -- United States.; Legal assistance to prisoners -- United States.; Clippings (information artifacts); Radio scripts.; Speeches.; Scrapbooks.; Jewish socialists -- United States.; Socialists -- New York (State) -- New York.; New York (N.Y.) -- Politics and government -- 20th century.; Hillquit, Morris, 1869-1933; Nearing, Scott, 1883-1983.; Laidler, Harry W. (Harry Wellington), 1884-1970; Solomon, Charles
- Series I: Papers
  - Adultery, 1951-1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cassidy, Robert, 1942-1947 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Biographical: Clippings, Memorabilia, Obituaries, 1936-1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Cases (Box 1, Folder 3A)
  - Certificates (Oversize), 1904-1947 (Box Shared Tamiment MSOS005, Folder 1, Box Shared Tamiment 006, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Clippings, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Clippings, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Clippings, 1955 (Box 1, Drawer 19)
  - Clippings, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Clippings, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Clippings, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Clippings, 1959-1968 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Clippings, Yiddish, nd (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "Confidence" Operations, 1951-1962 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1916-1944 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1946-1957 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1958-1962 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Debates, Radio Broadcasts, Speeches: Part 1, 1916-1960, nd (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Debates, Radio Broadcasts, Speeches: Part 2, 1916-1960, nd (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Delinquency, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - General, 1920-1960 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Heat Complaints, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Independent Citizens' Committee for the Election of Herbert Lehman as United States Senator, Nov 1949 (Box 2, Folder 6A)
  - Labor Day, AFL-CIO: Part 1, 1952-1956 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Labor Day, AFL-CIO: Part 2, 1952-1956 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Manuscripts, nd (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Morals, 1954-1957 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Pornography, Publishing Rights, etc., 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Sabbath Law, 1956-1959 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Schwartz, Joe, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Tinston, Albert, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Vending Machines, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Writings, Published, 1924-1950 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Series II: Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbook 1, 1931-1931 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook 2, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook 3, 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Scrapbook 4, 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook, Fragile: Part 1, 1935-1938 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, Fragile: Part 2, 1939-1941 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, Fragile: Part 3, 1940-1954 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Series III: Fragile Originals
  - Fragile Originals from Box 1, 1916, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Fragile Originals from Box 2, 1938, 1958, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)